Sr. Network Engineer

Sr. Network Engineer - Hexagon US Federal

Honolulu, HI - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/fe316658e1e09871

Network and Fiber Optic engineer, Project Manager, with over 20 years of experience in the Information Technology industry, which includes networking, electrical, and communication expertise. I demonstrate tremendous leadership skills, able to excel within a team, troubleshooting knowledge, network management, and client coordination.

Willing to relocate to: San Diego, CA - Phoenix, AZ - Denver, CO

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr. Network Engineer

Hexagon US Federal - March 2017 to Present

- Network engineer for installation and maintenance of a Naval secured network.
- Design and implement a secured network across 3 geographic locations meeting DOD and DOE security requirements.
- Installation, configuration and support of TCP/IP, Routing, OSPF, BGP, Radius, ATM, DWDM, SONET, MPLS, SDH, TDM, VPN, WAN, LAN, WLAN, VLAN, Cisco Routers, Switches, Firewalls, Network Administration and network wiring.
- Perform switch/router IOS upgrades and maintenance.
- Perform network security scans to determine network vulnerability. Help develop and implement plans of action to resolve any VM's that arise. Develop POA&M. Implement STIG's.
- Implementing latest technologies to continuously monitor the network and reduce downtime.
- Provide remote assistance to clients to minimize network down time to ongoing projects.
- Maintain cryptographic equipment through Taclanes for encryption of secure data on the network.

Network Engineer Fiber

ITC Service Group / Hawaiian Telecom - May 2013 to March 2017

- Project Manager for installation and maintenance of IT systems to include IP addressing, MAC filtering, port forwarding, and router configuration for clients.
- Level 2 and level 1 install configuration and support. TCP/IP, Routing, ATM, DWDM, SONET, SDH and TDM, DNS, WAN, LAN, WLAN, Cisco Routers, Switches, Firewalls, Network Administration and network wiring.
- Provide oversight and hands-on installation/repair of VDSL systems delivered through advanced Fiber Optic and copper network infrastructure.
- Install, Terminate, and Test (no-polish) Fiber Optic lines to client sites which include enterprise and residential sites.
- Voice, Data, and video through VDSL and RF technology.
- Provide remote assistance to clients to minimize down time utilizing USAMS, DSLAMS, fiber optic and twisted pair troubleshooting.

Partner / Network Engineer / Project Manager

Advanced Interior Electronics - May 2008 to May 2013

• Lead manager for the Residential and Commercial Audio/Video and Automation Installation Group.

- Responsible for network system design, installation, and maintenance of client hardware/software. Equipment and systems include audio/video, security cameras, card access systems, biometrics, etc.
- Installation, configuration, and support of WAN, LAN, WLAN, VLAN, TCP/IP Routers, Switches, Firewalls, Network Administration and network wiring.
- Provide oversight and hands-on experience for the installation and repair of IP based automation systems. Performed software and hardware design, installation and maintenance.
- Hired and trained new employees. Developed standard operating procedures (SOP's) for current and future technicians. Created employee handbooks and disciplinary policies.
- Project management. Worked with sales force, technicians and end users at all stages of the project. Coordinated purchasing, storage, and installation of materials for jobs. Developed manuals for end users that easily described the automation of all the integrated electronics.
- System Design. Attended manufacture training sessions. Helped guide and design projects with the sales force, optimizing the interoperability of the multitude of audio/video and automation products.
- Created job flow diagrams and integrated project database systems.
- Created standard operating processes (SOP) for fleet purchase, design, and maintenance schedules.
- Managed and streamlined quarterly and annual budgets.
- Helped grow the business from 20 employees to over 50. In that time I also helped increase the gross revenue each year. Went from a \$550,000 company in 2007 to a \$4M in 2012.

Owner / Network Engineer

Reasonable Audio and Video - January 2005 to May 2008

- Started, maintained, and ran the Residential and Commercial Audio Video Installation Group.
- Responsible for network system design, installation, and maintenance of client hardware/software. Equipment and systems include audio/video, security cameras, card access systems, biometrics, etc.
- Installation, configuration, and support of WAN, LAN, WLAN, VLAN, TCP/IP Routers, Switches, Firewalls, Network Administration and network wiring.
- Provide oversight and hands-on experience for the installation and repair of IP based automation systems. Performed software and hardware design, installation and maintenance.
- Responsible for sales, project design, and hiring/training of employees.
- Scheduling, purchasing, and management of jobs.

VDSL Network Technician

Qwest - February 2000 to March 2007

- Installed and repaired VDSL systems on the telephony network.
- · Voice, Data, and video of VDSL.
- · Provided remote troubleshooting for customers utilizing USAMS, DSLAMS, twisted pair troubleshooting.
- Extensive customer interaction and education in all areas of the phoenix metropolitan area.

Technician

VDSL Network - January 1999 to February 2000

- Installed and repaired VDSL systems on the telephony network.
- · Voice, Data, and video of VDSL.
- Provided remote troubleshooting for clients. USAMS, DSLAMS, twisted pair troubleshooting. Bridge tap removal.
- Extensive customer interaction and education in all areas of the phoenix metropolitan area.

Aircraft Electrical and Environmental Systems Technician

AIR FORCE/Italy - October 1995 to October 1998

• Installed and repaired electrical systems on F-16 aircraft.

- Maintain detailed logs of service and repairs.
- Maintained a Secret Security Clearance.

EDUCATION

BS in Information Technology Network Security

Western Governors University - Utah July 2017 to June 2020

SKILLS

DSL (10+ years), Excel (10+ years), F-16 (3 years), Project Manager (8 years), training (8 years), Network Administration (10+ years), Tele (10+ years)

CERTIFICATIONS/LICENSES

Cisco Certified Entry Networking Technician (CCENT)

March 2017 to March 2020

CompTIA Security+

July 2016 to July 2019

CompTIA Network+

July 2016 to July 2019

CompTIA A+

December 2015 to December 2018

Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA)

June 2017 to June 2020

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Skills

- Secret Clearance Interim / NACLC level
- 20 years of Network Engineering/Administration, IT, Telecom skills, Fiber Optics, Data, DSL, VDSL, Phone.
- 8 Years lead project manager for client Network, Audio, Video, and Automation Systems.
- Electrical and environmental systems training through the U.S. Air Force specifically for F-16 infrastructure
- Windows XP through Windows 10 qualified, Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Publisher, Access)